Guide to the Alexander M. Drummond papers, 1917-1956.
Drummond, Alexander M. papers, 1917-1956
- Series V. Photographs and Glass Slides
  - The Master Builder glass negative, March 5, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - The Master Builder glass negative, March 5, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - The Master Builder glass negative, March 5, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - The Master Builder glass negative, March 5, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Donovan Affair glass negative, February 13, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Wings Over Europe glass negative, December 2, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 42)
  - Wings Over Europe glass negative, December 2, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 43)
  - Wings Over Europe glass negative, December 2, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 44)
  - Wings Over Europe glass negative, December 2, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Wings Over Europe glass negative, December 2, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 46)
  - Wings Over Europe glass negative, December 2, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 47)
  - Wings Over Europe glass negative, December 2, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 48)
  - Contrast photograph negative, undated (Box 29, Folder 49)
  - Wings Over Europe glass and photograph negatives, undated (Box 29, Folder 50)
  - The Winslow Boy photograph negatives, November 3 - 4, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 51)
  - The Women Have Their Way photograph negatives, undated (Box 29, Folder 52)
  - Yankee Land photograph negatives, October 18 - 19, November 1 - 2, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 53)
  - Yankee Makes a Bargain photograph negatives, undated (Box 29, Folder 54)
  - Yellow Jacket photograph negatives, undated (Box 29, Folder 55)
  - You Touched Me! photograph negatives, October 21 - 23, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 56)
- Series VI. Clippings
  - Theatre Related Items, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Clippings and Notes on Published Plays and Books, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Articles on Speech, 1921 - 1954 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - New York Themed Publications, 1940 - 1953 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    State Fair Guide; Historical
  - Up-state New York Information, 1927 - 1954 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    World's Fair; Brochures; Town Publications; Historical
  - New York Information, 1934 - 1940 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Historical; Speech
  - New York Information, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Newspapers; Photographs; Brochures; Historical; Ithaca
  - Theatre and Arts Publications, 1925 - 1956 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Theatre and Arts Publications, 1933 - 1938 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Theatre and Arts Publications, 1935 - 1955 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    New Theatre magazine
  - Theatre and Arts Publications, 1925 - 1951 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    Electronic Equipment
  - Theatre and Arts Publications, 1933 - 1942 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Ithaca Clippings, January 1952 - February 1955 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Little Theatre Convention; Prize Plays; Newspaper clippings, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Theatre Clippings; African-American Players; Catalogues, 191 9 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Misc. Newspaper Clippings, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Misc. Theatre Clippings, 1926 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    Growth; News; Anecdotes; Arena; Personalities
  - Misc. Newspaper Clippings, 1947 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    Theatre; Drama; Plays
  - Liberal Education, 1949 - 1953 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    Modern Education (divided into two folders)
  - Music, 1949 - 1953 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    Opear; Jenny Lind; Metropolitan; Orchestral
  - New Production Reviews, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    New York and Other U.S. States
  - Book Reviews, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    Shakespeare; Theatre; Drama
  - Radio and Television, 1936 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    John Crosby
  - Theatre and Arts Publications, 1942 - 1943 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    Wagner
  - Miscellaneous Newspapers and Clippings, undated (Box 20)
- Series VII. Scripts
  - Scripts, 1940 - 1946 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    The Real Thing; Mr. Swizzle Reads a Story (2x); No Ties; Take It Or Leave It Alone; Repeat Performance; The Ripple
  - Rural Plays, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Plays produced, but with which not much can be done", 1939 - 1940 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Good Regional Ideas, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Good Regional Ideas, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Plays Submitted for Competition, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Plays Retained for Possible Use, 1946 and undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Non-regional and non-rural
  - Student Plays, 1938 and undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Play Scripts by Helen O. Lathers, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - The Forest Rose by Samuel Woodworth, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Heerman's Prize Entries, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Heerman's Prize Play, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - NY State Plays and Class Plays before 1953, 1950 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    "some with promise and possibly worth reworking"
  - Play Scripts, 1950 - 1951 and undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Play Scripts, 1950 and undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Play Scripts, 1951 and undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - NY State Play Project Script, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    1st Prize, The Song of Scanagara
  - NY State Play Project Scripts, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    1st Prize and Honorable Mention
  - NY State Play Project Scripts, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    1st Prize, The Opened Road by Grace Cornell
  - Forbes Heerman Entires and Student Plays, 1941 - 1946 and undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
    Unsorted (divided into two folders)
  - New York State Plays Produced and Published, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Play Fragments, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - New York State Play: Family Co-operative, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - New York State Plays and State Fair Plays, 1953 - 1954 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Divided into two folders
  - Two Cornell Dramatic Club Plays, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Musical: Glorious to View, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Term Papers for Dramam 48b, 1946 and undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Two Plays by Michael Chayes, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - The Strike by Richard J. Davidson, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Student Plays, 1946 - 1950 and undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Music Hall Show, March, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Various short scripts and production information
  - Student Plays by G.O. Allen and Edward D. Ray, 1946 - 1950 and undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - List of Possible Play Productions (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Class Plays Retained, Spring 1950 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Two scripts by Marion miller and three by Munroe Scott
  - Heerman Prize Play: Temper with Tyrrany by J. Fairchild, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Script: He Wears an Oak Leaf in His Hat by Elanor Franz, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Plays Retained from 1949 Regional Playwriting Contest, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Plays Retained from 1950 Regional Playwriting Contest, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - New York State Play Contest Rejected Scripts, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Misc. Plays, 1939 - 1950 and undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Misc. Play Materials, 1928 - 1934 and undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
    Skits; Scripts and fragments; Stage direction; Production notes; etc
  - Script: The Bear's Secret, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    For Primary Grades
  - 4 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Honeymoon Special; The Fraternity Loses a Member; Love and Glory; The Knitting Dream
  - 7 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Till Death Do Us Part; They Waited For Silk; All's Right With the World; Once to Ever Man; Soldier's Bonus; The Fourth Place; The South Does It
  - 6 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Ruloff; The Return; Regina Returns; Raisin' the Devil; The Man With the Missing Toe; Rooms for Tourists
  - Scripts, 1890 - 1942 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Plays; Short Scenes; Monologues; etc
  - Short Scripts, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - New York State Plays, 1949 - 1950 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - 2 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Mr. Swizzle Reads a Story; Strangers Rest Here
  - Script and Letter from Alex Panas to Dr. MaCalmon, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    The Bastards
  - Script: The Wild Duck, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Script: The Tarnished, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - 6 Scripts, 1937 - 1939 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    The Broken Chain; Bury the Bard (2x); The Bride; Bath at Cayuga Ridge (2x); The Constant Lover; Auctions Aren't Endings
  - 3 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Crackerbarrel Joe (2x); Cash on Hand; Chenango Crone
  - Script, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Untitled and Undated
  - Land Grant College Radio Program Scripts, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Scripts, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    An Inn one the Catskill Pike; The Finger Lakes; Taughannock Stone; A Yankee Makes a Bargain; Radio Script
  - Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
    York State Mill-Town; Strangers Rest Here; The Cardiff Giant; New York State Plays
  - Script: Colonel Maecham's Big Cheese, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - 4 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
    Rainin' the Devil; Mixing Up the Rent; Hymn to Victory; The Hornin'
  - 3 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
    Puppets; The Public Universal Friend; For the Public Welfare
  - 4 Scripts, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    York State Mill-Town; The Story of Muller Hill; Doing Nothing; My Ideal
  - 4 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
    How the Canal Came to Buffalo; Judge Whipple Officiates; Letters of a President; A Little House in Angelica
  - 2 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    Old Tom; Out of the Night
  - Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
    Hard Cider; Honeymoon; and more untitled scripts
  - 6 Scripts, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Freedom of Speech; A Fable for Two; The Family Co-op; Family Co-operative; Revised to Order; Farmer Franklin's Folly
  - 2 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
    Flight From Connecticut Hill, or A Borderline Case; The End of the World
  - 4 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
    Crackers for Communion; Devil's in the Pig-Pen; Don't Talk!; The Door
  - 3 Scripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
    All Alone in the Hills; The Puppets; Wild Hills (2x)
  - Script: Bugles at Noon, undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Script: Bugles at Noon, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    With edits
  - Script: Bugles at Noon, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - 2 Scripts, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Spankin'; The Slope of the Hill
  - 5 Scripts, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    The Ripple; Rehearsal; Strangers Rest Here; The Parasite; Second Mortgage
  - 5 Scripts, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Rome Stall; The Man With the Missing Toe; Raisin' the Devil; Who Is Wellington?; A Yankee Makes a Bargain
  - 4 Scripts, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    A Day in the Vineyard; The Battle of Dutch Hill; Auctions Aren't Endings; Country Slicker
  - 6 Scripts, 1940s (Box 19, Folder 7)
    The Ghost at Guy Park Manor; The Great Tunnel Escape; Family Co-operative; Fractions; Farm Literature; Fishin' Weather
  - 5 Scripts, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Nothing Doing; Let's Get on with the Marryin'; The House by the Side of the Road; Honeymoon; Untitled script
  - 4 Scripts, 1940s (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Plain Folks; Public Universal Friend; Out of the Night; The Other Road
  - Radio Program Series, 1939 - 1940 and undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Script: Calculated Risk, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Script: A Passion Play, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
    By Georg Fuchs
  - Script: Stony Island, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Script: Wild Hills, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Script: The Grecian Captive, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - An Exercise Containing a Dialogue and an Ode, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Script: Soil, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Script: The Old Peabody Pew, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
- Series VIII. Programs
  - International Programs, 1934 and undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Including Chinese and Yiddish
  - New York City Productions programs, 1935 - 1942 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Federal Theatre Project; Labor Stage, 1936 and undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Programs from smaller New York theatres, 1910 - 1947 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Metropolitan Opera, 1930 - 1931 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Programs from other University theatres, 1913 - 1956 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Cornell University theatre and concert programs, 1904 - 1951 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Cornell University theatre and concert programs, 1904 - 1950 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Cornell University theatre and concert programs, 1914 - 1950 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Cornell University theatre and concert programs, 1921 - 1950 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Ithaca, NY Programs, 1915 - 1950 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Strand Theatre, Ithaca, NY, 1931 - 1946 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Lyceum Theatre, Ithaca, NY, 1914 - 1923 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Finger Lakes Drama Festival, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - New York State Fair Theatre, 1951 - 1954 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Pasadena Community Playhouse, 1929 - 1931 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Programs from other local theatres outside of Ithaca, 1912 - 1965 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Jim Dandy, 1941 - 1942 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Misc. theatre programs and publications, 1913 - 1956 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - NY Theatre Playbills and Programs, undated (Box 32)
  - NY and other state Playbills and Programs, 1927 - 1956 (?) (Box 33)
  - NY Theatre Playbills and Programs, undated (Box 34)
- Series IX. Oversized Items
  - Musical Scores; National institute of Social Sciences medal; Diplomas and Honoraria, 1942 and undated (Box 21)
  - NY State Plays Project scrapbook; County Theatre Records Scrapbook, 1938 - 1941 (Box 31)
  - Stage design drawing for H.M.S. Pinafore show at Bailey Hall by C. Lewis. (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Poster for the Cardiff Giant 1869 show, drawings for stage design and lighting, Cornell Theater building plans. (Mapcase-folder 2)
  - Cornell Theater building plans. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Charcoal drawing of A.M. Drummond by Christian Midjo, probably in the 1930s. (Folder 1)
- Series X. Audio
  - Speak-O-Phone audiodisc, also discs of public speaking class - students recordings and critiques., 1942 and undated (Box 24)
- Series XI. Miscellaneous
  - File Cards, undated (Box 9)
  - NY State Plays Project, 1948 - 1952 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    American Agriculturalist; State Fair
  - NY State Plays Project, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Play lists; Programs; Finances; University theatre
  - NY State Plays Project, 1936 - 1939 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Programs; University theatre; Newspaper clippings
  - NY State Plays Project, 1938 - 1939 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Misc; Newspaper clippings
  - File of New York State Plays Project, 1947 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Plays; Writers; Finances; Cornell Plays; Themes, etc.
  - NY State Plays Project, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Scripts; Newspaper clippings
  - NY State Plays Project, 1935 - 1939 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Scripts; Correspondence; Little Theatre Conference; more
  - NY State Plays Project, 1939 - 1943 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    NY State Little Theatre Conference; Personal Correspondence
  - NY State Plays Project, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Publicity; Statistics; Robert Gard plays
  - NY State Plays Project Forms, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Plans for projects similar to NY State Plays Project, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - NY State Plays and Upstate NY Plays, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Notes and lists
  - American Agriculturalist Rural Play Project, New Playwriters' Project, 1946 - 1947 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Rural and folk culture; National Theatre Conference
  - Rural Drama Project, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - American Agriculturalist Play Material, 1949 - 1950 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Correspondence; Grange lecturers
  - State Fairs and County Theatre, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Country Theatre, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    State fairs; Barnyard theatre; Cornell Dramatic Club
  - Little Country Theatre, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Photographs and more
  - Set Design Sketches, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Heartbreak House Set Design, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Original Sketches for Productions, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - "The Critic" Design by Frank Lopez, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Outline for Textbook, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    History of Theatre in America
  - Misc. Correspondence and Documents, 1930 - 1952 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Misc. Correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Uncle Vanya film premier, Benefit for Drummond memorial fund, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Drummond memorial correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence re: Drummond retirement dinner, May 1 - 13, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Drummond retirement dinner, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    Seating plan; Guestbook; and other related items
  - Speeches given at Drummond retirement dinner, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    Edited and unedited copies
  - Drummond Retirement, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    Newspaper articles; Dinner documents; Correspondence; Drummond fund
  - Correspondence, 1947 - 1950 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    Drummond fund; Carolyn and Robert Treman
  - Photo of Drummond +3; Finances; Guestbook for party and signatures, 1948 - 1949 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Drummond Fund, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Notes and verse from friends, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Drummond Idea, June 5, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    Speech given by R. Gard in honor of Drummond
  - Reception, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Citizen House - Bath, England, 1932 - 1933 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    Little Theatre
  - Since Thou Art Dead, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Museum of Modern Art film library, undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Comfort Tyler notes and legal papers, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Comfort Tyler House Photographs, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Comfort Tyler Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1929 - 1940 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Historical Sketch of Comfort Tyler in Onondaga, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Various Articles on Theatre, 1916 - 1954 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Professional Theatre, 1936 - 1954 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Newspaper articles; Kabuki; Photographs
  - Broadway Reviews and How a Critic (Kerr) Judges a Play, 1938 - 1951 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Newspaper articles
  - Speech, 1929 - 1955 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Quarterly Journal of Speech; Speech therapy; Speech education
  - Classic Quotes on Modern Problems, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Plato; Aristotle (Divided into two folders)
  - Modern and Ancient Architecture, 1949 - 1954 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Sullivan; Wrigh; Newspaper articles; Time articles
  - T.S Eliot, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    The Three Voices of Poetry in The Atlantic Monthly
  - George Jean Nathan, 1948 - 1952 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    The Theatre; Newspaper articles
  - Hemingway, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    The Atlantic Serial article
  - Shakespeare articles, 1938 - 1952 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - G.B. Shaw, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Malvern Festival article
  - Saroyan article, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Fritz Erler, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Munich Art Theatre
  - George Fuchs, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Munich Art Theatre; German Form
  - Misc. Cinema articles, 1945 - 1954 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Newspaper and journal articles
  - The Importance of Speech Courses in the Liberal Arts Curriculum by Wilbur Gilman, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Entertainments and Recreations of Pioneer Days in Ithaca by John Brooks, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Lenov and Shaw, 1902 - 1947 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Selections of themes, treatments, and methods; Writers as cultural conscience
  - The Wisconsin Idea, 1951 - 1956 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    Seasonal programs; Newspaper articles; University theatre
  - Exit the Cad by G. Finletter, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - On Comedy by F. Robortellus, July, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Puritanism and Theatre, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Revolution in the Theatre, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    Typescript (divided into two folders)
  - Misc. Newspaper Clippings, 1951- 1954 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - A National Theatre, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Competition, 1946 - 1947 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    Notes on sports, railroad strike and cock fighting
  - Books, December 27, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    Reviews and catalogues
  - Scrapbook of Misc. Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Various Reprinted Scholarly Articles on Theatre, 1944 - 1954 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    Signed copies by Ogden, Herrick, Murphy, West, Hultzin and Coon
  - Gordon Craig Patents, 1910 - 1951 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Programs and Newsletters, 1930 - 1942 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Misc. Materials; Non-legitimate Theatre, 1944 - 1952 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    Newspaper clippings
  - Films, 1936 - 1952 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    Reviews; Sex; Puppets; Bob Jones University; Drive-Ins; Androcles
  - Cornell Graduates in Plays and Films, 1924 - 1963 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    Newspaper clippings and articles
  - Cornell University History, 1939 - 1954 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    Newspaper clippings and articles; News; Sports; Theatre; etc.
  - Willard Straight Hall, 1950 - 1954 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    Anniversary program; Newspaper clipping; Notes
  - American and NY State History Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Misc. Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 11, Folder 42)
    Cornell; Theatre; Reviews
  - Notes on Rulloff, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    Script for Contest
  - Valley Vagabonds, 1940 - 1941 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    History; Information; Playbill
  - Newfield, NY, 1900 - 1941 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Newfield First Methodist Church; Newspaper; Church Directory
  - Newfield, NY, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Skits for Newfield Methodist Church; Photographs
  - Quiz Questions, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Steamboat Frontenac, July 29, 1907 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - History of Educational Organizations Interested in Theatre, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Drama League of America; National Theatre Conference; American Educational Theatre Association; William Halstead
  - Thesis: The Art of the Mise en Scene, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Thomas Broadhurst, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Cornell Bulletin for Homemakers: Songs, June, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - How To Prepare and Act a Part, November, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Men in White Review, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Sidney Kingsley
  - "Plays for Little Theatres", undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Community Theatre Exchange, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Translation of Diderot's Response to the Letter of MME. Riccoboni, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - The Rural Community and The Drama, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Historical Essays, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Central New York Historian's Conference; Central New York College Association; more misc., 1849 - 1941 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Federal Theatre Project, December, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Stanislavsky, 1949 - 1950 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Forward and Backward in the Theatre by Howard Clurman, October 30, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Arena Theatre, 1929 - 1951 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    University Theatre; Newspaper articles; Magazines
  - SEAS Workshop Discussions, March 29, 1950 - April 19, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Higher and Liberal Education, 1940 - 1951 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    Practicality of a liberal education; Ends of a liberal education; Reports; Newspaper articles; Brochures
  - World Assembly of Youth, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    General Assembly information; General information
  - Late 19th Century Theatre Advertisements, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Gleanings in Europe: Volume 2: England by J.F. Cooper, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - New York State Citizens' Council Information, January - June, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Talma on The Actor's Art, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
    Preface by Henry Irving
  - Plan for a Collection of Manuscripts and Newspapers Bearing on the History of Up-state New York, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
    From Edmund E. Day
  - Early History of English Studies, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)